Here's a concrete example of the data cleaning process: defining, coding, and testing.
以下是数据清理流程的具体示例 涉及方案确定、代码编写和效果检验三步
So gathering was completed,
现在数据收集已经完成
imported the Pandas library and read this animals.csv file into a data frame called DF.
也已导入了 pandas 库并把这个 animal.csv 文件以DataFrame的形式读取出来 将DataFrame命名为 DF
Then visual assessment was done in Pandas and two quality issues were noted.
视觉评估也已在 pandas 中完成了 我们发现了两个质量问题
The letters bb before every animal name and
即每个动物名称前多出来的字母 bb
an exclamation mark instead of a period for the decimal in body weight and brain weight.
还有体重和脑重的小数用了感叹号而不是句点
Notice that these assessments are observations.
注意这些评估结果叫做观察评述
So let's get cleaning. The first step, defining.
现在我们开始清理 第一步 确定方案
Rather than a strict observation like in
与评估文件要用严谨的观察评述不同
our assessment documentation, defining uses verbs.
确定方案这一步要用动词
It's a call to action to fix the issue we observed.
因为这是种行动召唤 目的是解决我们观察到的问题
For example, this works.
比如 这一句有效
Remove bb before every animal name.
把所有动物名称前的 bb 删除掉
The verb or action word being removed.
这里用了动词 也即行为词“删除”
You can get as detail as you like.
你想写多具体就可以写多具体
Whatever you find helps you best when coding next.
只要你觉得对接下来写代码那一步有帮助 就都可以写下来
So this could very well be,
所以这里写成这样更好
remove bb for every animal name using string slicing,
用字符串切片来删除所有动物名称前面的 bb
specifying the tool or function method etc.
也就是具体说明要用什么工具、函数或方法等
that you'll use to actually fix this issue using code.
来借助代码解决问题
A second example for the exclamation mark issue.
以感叹号问题为第二个例子
Replace exclamation mark with period in body weight and brain weight columns.
把体重和脑重两列的感叹号换成句点
Those are defined cleaning operations.
以上就是确定好的清理操作
Okay, so step two, coding.
好了 来到第二步 编写代码
This is actually doing the thing you mentioned in your definition.
也就是把方案确定那一步提及的东西落实下来
And for us in this course, we're going to leverage the Pandas's library.
而在本课程中 我们将利用 pandas 的库来完成这一步
To fix the first issue, we'll use string slicing and to fix the second one,
要解决第一个问题 我们可以用字符串切片 至于第二个问题
we'll use Pandas's string.replace method each operating on their own column.
我们要用 pandas 的 str. replace 方法 每一句会分别应用于相应的列
Animal, body weight, brain weight.
即动物体重和脑重两列
So now it's testing time.
然后就到了检验这一步
The third step in the data cleaning process.
也即数据清理流程的第三步
This is making sure our code worked.
这一步目的在于检验代码是否奏效
The simplest way of doing so is just visually assessing your data set again which we'll
最简单的检验方法是再视觉评估一次数据集
do for this data set because it's pretty small and everything looks good here.
这也正是我们要对这个数据集做的事 因为这个数据集很小 现在看来没什么问题了
Visual assessment works here but we can also use programmatic assessments,
这个情景下可以用视觉评估来检验效果 不过我们也可以用程序评估、
search statements, Pandas's built in testing methods and functions for example.
查询语句以及 pandas 内置的检验方法和函数等